# Giwoo Lee

Hangul: 이지우 / 李支右

# Front End / Full Stack Engineer

6+ years advancing in the IT industry as a **Web Application and Solutions Engineer** in developing web applications for B2C applications. Shaped products using Data Engineering with BI, Mainframes (batch processing), and Web/Mobile development.

Enthusiast about Code Design Patterns, Rich Web/Native UX, Web App Performance, and Machine Learning.

•	Seoul, South Korea
<b>(</b>	+82 (010) 6824-8998
$\boxtimes$	gglee89@gmail.com (Preferable)
C	https://github.com/gglee89
<b>(1)</b>	https://giwoolee.com

## **Technical Skills**

Main programing languages:

JavaScript, Python.

D 1 D 1 D 1 /T'1 '

Firebase, MySQL, MongoDB, GraphQL.

**Back End Frameworks/Libraries:** 

NodeJS-Express, Python-Django

Front End Frameworks/Libraries:

ES6/Next, Webpack, SVG, SCSS, Responsive Design, React, Redux, WebSocket.

**Testing Frameworks/Libraries:** 

Jest, Mocha.

Dev Ops:

**Database:** 

Git, Docker, Kubernetes, CircleCI, AWS, Google Cloud Platform.

## **Work Experience**

## **Udacity -** *Mentor Front End Nanodegree (Remote)*

Feb 2019-Today

Mentor Front End dev students on a weekly and daily basis over video and slack on completing their courses. Main focus in Advanced JavaScript, Design Patterns, and CSS (Responsiveness, Modularity).

#### FSU iSchool - Research Assistant

Tallahassee, FL, USA | Aug 2019-Aug 2020 (1 Year)

Research on Machine Learning and Natural Language Processing (NLP). Application development of Online Polygraph for experimental studies and data collection purposes. Advisor: Prof. PhD. Shuyuan Mary Ho

#### **Rocky Robots -** *Software Engineer (Remote)*

Munich, Germany | Sep 2018-July 2019 (10 Months)

Design and development of German startup's mobile app Rocky AI "Accountability Assistant" incubated at TechStars in Munich, Germany. Deployed both iOS/Android app with React Native, Firebase, NodeJS and Python.

## **Proof Suite -** Front End Developer (Contractor)

Seoul, South Korea | Feb 2018-July 2018 (6 months)

Led the concept and full UI/Front implementation of crypto currency trading and analysis platform, namely AVOCADO. Deployed application's front-end with React, Redux, Webpack, Stockcharts, D3.js, Socket.io

# Marshall Goldsmith SCC - Front End Developer

Seoul, South Korea | Jan 2017-Mar 2018 (1 year 1 month)

Led Marshall's "Leadership Growth" reviewer platform development used as a catalyst for executive coaches to migrate their support material to the web with stack consisted of PHP, Laravel, React, Javascript, Webpack, SASS.

#### **Makestar -** Front End Developer (Contractor)

Seoul, South Korea | May 2017-Nov 2017 (6 months)

Revamped the UI and optimized the usability and performance for the KPOP Global Crowdfunding website.

## **SAP Labs Korea -** Front End Developer Internship

Seoul, South Korea | Aug 2015-Feb 2016 (6 months)

Led web app's UI/UX concept and implementation in conjoint work with the QA (Quality Assurance) and Development department. Deployed app to expedite Hana Database crash report analysis previously done in 3 days to be done in 1 day.

#### **FNC Inc. -** Software Developer Internship

Oxford, MS, USA | Jun 2013-May 2014 (1 year)

Provided support on home appraisal web application built over C#/.Net, TFS, SQL Server, and KnockoutJS.

## **Amdocs** - System Analyst Internship

Sao Paulo, SP, Brazil | Apr 2011-May 2012 (1 year)

Implemented and maintained billing services for Claro Brazil Telecom. Deployed services and fixes in COBOL and C in mainframe for batch invoice processing.

## **Technolab Corp.** - BI Consultant Internship

Sao Paulo, SP, Brazil | Sep 2010-Mar 2011 (7 months)

Data Engineer assisting full implementation of Oracle's BI solutions over DW, OLAP, ETL, and Database Administration.

## **Education**

Florida State University- Computer Science Courses focused on NLP + ML

May 2020

**Ajou University -** *MSc Information Systems [Not completed]* (Full Scholarship - GPA 3.7/4.0)

December 2017

University of Mississippi - Visiting student at the CS department (Full Scholarship funded by the Brazilian CAPES Program - GPA 3.5/4.0)

May 2012 - May 2013

Faculdade Impacta de Tecnologia - BSc Information Systems

August 2009 - June 2014

## Certification

<b>Developing Application with Google Cloud Platform Specialization</b> - Coursera	September 2018
Udacity - React Nanodegree	March 2018
Udacity - Front End Nanodegree	December 2017
Udacity - Full Stack Nanodegree	July 2017

## Language

Portuguese (Brazil)	Fluent
English	Fluent
Korean	Fluent
Spanish	Intermediate